Baatchia Riyadh

Fullstack Web Developer

Location: Setif, Algeria Phone: (+213) 659 46 73 28

Email: baatchia_Riyadh@protonmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/baatchia-riyadh

Portfolio: riyadh-dev.github.io/portfolio GitHub: github.com/riyadh-dev

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT SKILLS

• Languages: TypeScript/JavaScript/NodeJS, HTML, CSS, SASS/SCSS, C#, WPF, XAML, WinForms

- Frameworks and libraries: ReactJS, NextJS, SolidJS, Tailwind CSS, tRPC, Zod, Prisma, drizzle-orm, Next-auth, ExpressJS, GraphQL, WebSockets, RecoilJS, Jotai, React Query, Redux Toolkit, MUI, Bootsrap, Chakra UI, .NET.
- Data Bases: MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Plantescale.
- Tools: Git, GitHub, Turborepo, ParcelJS, Husky, ViteJS.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

- E-Commerce app: a fullstack e commerce web app with a cart system and strip checkout
 - Teck stack: TypeScript, NextJS, Tailwind CSS, Strip, RecoilJS, Strip...
 - Repo: github.com/riyadh-dev/e-commerce-app
 - Link: e-commerce-app-self.vercel.app
- Airbnb clone: a fullstack property renting app
 - Teck stack: TypeScript, NextJS, Tailwind CSS, tRPC, Drizzle orm, Next-auth, MySQL(PlanetScale)...
 - Repo: github.com/riyadh-dev/airbnb-clone
 - Link: airbnb-clone-riyadh-dev.vercel.app
- Social media app: a fullstack web app with instant messaging, posting, friends, likes and more
 - Teck stack: TypeScript, React, Express, MongoDB, MUI, RecoilJS, React Query, React Router...
 - Repo: github.com/riyadh-dev/social-media-app
 - Link: social-media-app-eoga.onrender.com
- Instant messaging app: a fullstack web app with instant messaging and friending system and more
 - Teck stack: TypeScript, React, Express, MongoDB, MUI, RecoilJS, React Query, Turborepo...
 - Repo: github.com/riyadh-dev/messaging-app
 - Link: messaging-app-2b7q.onrender.com
- See more: riyadh-dev.github.io/portfolio/#projects

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Fluent in English

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

BJD IT Constantine, Algeria

Frontend web developer

2023

- Led the architecture and development of multiple front-end applications, with a focus on creating interactive dashboards.
- Implemented responsive design principles to optimize user experience across different devices.
- Integrated third-party APIs, including Firebase, to boost functionality and streamline processes.

SIRIUS SERVICES Setif, Algeria

Software Developer

2020 – 2022

- Developed various scripts to automate a variety of repetitive task to increase productivity and efficiency.
- Designed and develop an IEC101 Master Simulator to help company employees conduct site testing much easier.

FREELANCING Setif, Algeria

Software Developer

2019 - 2020

Designed and developed some simple applications for local small business

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

INSTITUTE OF ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING (EX-INELEC)

Boumerdes, Algeria

Masters in Computer Engineering

July 2019

- Graduated with B grading (grading is decided relative to other students).
- Developed a Full stack Web Application to facilitate the management of the Scientific Council of the institute.

ELECTRICITY AND GAS DISTRIBUTION ADMINISTRATION

Oum El Bouaghi, Algeria

INTERNSHIP

24/03/2018 - 05/04/2018

- Was responsible for daily backing up customers database.
- Was giving a basic walk-through on the IT department daily operations.

INSTITUTE OF ELECTRICAL AND ELECTRONICS ENGINEERING (EX-INELEC)

Boumerdes, Algeria

License in Electrical and Electronics Engineering

July 2017

ABOUT ME

Computer Science Master's graduate and skilled Full Stack Web Developer with expertise in frontend development using React and backend development with Node.js. Enthusiastic about learning and exploring the latest web technologies like SolidJS, Bun, and Astro.